<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Fruity Tropics</title>
    <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Fruity Tropics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fruitytropics.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understory</title>
      <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/understory.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/understory.html</guid>
      <description>Planting An Understory Orchard We live on 10 acres on the edge of a 100 acre jungle reserve, with a further contiguous 100 acres undeveloped. We&amp;rsquo;re between Corcovado and Quetzali national parks, in an area that local conservation groups are working to maintain and deepen as a wildlife corridor. Troops of monkeys come swinging through the garden multiple times a week, parrots and toucans are daily visitors, hummingbirds buzz between the canopy and the flowers in our front garden; we&amp;rsquo;ve recorded a puma on our trailcam, and a couple of weeks back I saw a pack of fifteen peccaries, some big enough to be bad news if you got on the wrong end of their intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango</title>
      <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/mango.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/mango.html</guid>
      <description>Mango Mangifera indica L.
Mango is an evergreen tree native to southern Asia, imported to the Americas in the sixteenth century. It can be pruned to remain a manageable size, but given the opportunity will grow to 40 meters in height. It bears a delicious sweet oblong fruit which can get to 10&amp;quot; in length, with a thin skin protecting a yellow juicy flesh around a large central seed.
Growing Mango We live on a reforested finca which used to have mango orchards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maracuya</title>
      <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/maracuya.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/maracuya.html</guid>
      <description>Maracuya (Passion Fruit) Passiflora edulis, Passiflora edulis var. flavicarpa Sims.
Passion Fruit is one of 550 species of the genus Passiflora. In Spanish, it&amp;rsquo;s referred to as maracuya, which can refer to either the yellow (flavicarpa) or purple varieties (the Blanke book refers to the purple as maracuya, but here on the pacific coast the yellow variety is much more available and is given the same name.) Commonly available from farmers markets and fruiterias in Costa Rica, it&amp;rsquo;s a oval fruit, typically around the size of an apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papaya</title>
      <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/papaya.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/papaya.html</guid>
      <description>Papaya Carica Papaya L.
Papaya is a mainstay of Latin American cuisine, and is likely native to the Americas. The plants are &amp;ldquo;tree like&amp;rdquo;, in that they have a soft woody stem, large lobed leaves, and grow to around 10 meters. However, they taper off in fruiting productivity at a relatively young age, and are frequently cut down at only 5 or 6 years old. Enormously productive, a single plant can produce 80 pounds of fruit in a single year, once fruiting gets underway (often around 6 months after planting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granadilla</title>
      <link>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/granadilla.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 15:37:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fruitytropics.com/posts/granadilla.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
