<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Fruity Tropics</title>
    <link>http://fruitytropics.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Fruity Tropics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://fruitytropics.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maracuya</title>
      <link>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/maracuya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/maracuya/</guid>
      <description>Maracuya (Passion Fruit) Passiflora edulis, Passiflora edulis var. flavicarpa Sims.
Passion Fruit is one of 550 species of the genus Passiflora. In Spanish, it&amp;rsquo;s referred to as maracuya, which can refer to either the yellow (flavicarpa) or purple varieties (the Blanke book refers to the purple as maracuya, but here on the pacific coast the yellow variety is much more available and is given the same name.) Commonly available from farmers markets and fruiterias in Costa Rica, it&amp;rsquo;s a oval fruit, typically around the size of an apple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papaya</title>
      <link>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/papaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/papaya/</guid>
      <description>Carica Papaya L.
Papaya Papaya is a mainstay of Latin American cuisine, and is likely native to the Americas. The plants are &amp;ldquo;tree like&amp;rdquo;, in that they have a soft woody stem, and large lobed leaves, and grow to around 10 meters. However, they taper off in fruiting productivity at a relatively young age, and are frequently cut down at only 5 or 6 years old. Enormously productive, a single plant can produce 80 pounds of fruit in a single year, once fruiting gets underway (often around 6 months after planting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granadilla</title>
      <link>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/granadilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 15:37:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fruitytropics.com/posts/granadilla/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
